A Guide to the Burnett Family Papers, 1881-1998
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Burnett Family Papers, 1881-1998
The Library of Virginia
44300
14 cubic feet (29 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Charles Ryland Burnett, III, Houston, Texas.
Biographical Information
Charles Ryland Burnett, Sr. was born in Richmond, Virginia on 14 October 1873. He was the son of Henry Cox Burnett and Mary Jane Caldwell. Burnett attended McGuire's University School and Richmond College (now the University of Richmond). He was employed by the First National Bank beginning in 1891, and served as assistant cashier, as vice-president, and as director. In 1926, he was elected vice-president and director of the First and Merchants National Bank in Richmond. Burnett married Eugenia Whyte Griffin (1889-1981) of Salem, Virginia on 10 October 1917. She was the daughter of Judge Wingfield Griffin and Claudine Booker. Eugenia Griffin attended Sweet Briar College, and was a member of the first graduating class in 1910. She later served on their Board of Directors. Charles Ryland Burnett, Sr. died on 10 January 1949. Eugenia Griffin Burnett died on 15 April 1981. They are both buried in Hollywood Cemetery in Richmond.
Their son, Charles Ryland Burnett, Jr. was born in Richmond on 7 October 1918. He attended Episcopal High School in Alexandria, and then graduated from the University of Virginia. During World War II, he attained the rank of lieutenant commander aboard the U.S.S. Croatan. Burnett married Miriam Louise Weston in Richmond on 17 April 1954. Weston was born on 7 March 1922 in Toronto, Canada. She was the daughter of W. Garfield Weston and Reta Lila Howard. Weston graduated from Stanford University. She was chair of the W. Garfield Weston Foundation for 30 years. Charles and Miriam Weston had one son, Charles Ryland Burnett III (b. 1956). The family resided in a number of different countries, where the elder Burnett served as president or on the board of directors of various companies owned by W. Garfield Weston, including the Belmont Manor Golf and Country Club in Bermuda, Howardsgate Holdings Limited, and Walter's Biscuits Limited. Charles Ryland Burnett, Jr. died on 27 August 2004 in Toronto. Miriam Louise Weston Burnett died in Richmond on 12 March 2008. They are both buried in Hollywood Cemetery.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1881-1998, of the Burnett family of Richmond, Virginia, and Florida, Bermuda, England, South Africa, and Canada, namely Charles Ryland Burnett, Sr. (1873-1949), Eugenia Griffin Burnett (1889-1981), Charles Ryland Burnett, Jr. (1918-2004), and Miriam Louise Weston Burnett (1923-2008). The collection includes correspondence, clippings, diaries, financial records, greeting cards, insurance papers, naval service records and publications, photographs, school work and class notes, scrapbooks, travel brochures, and other materials.
The earliest correspondence in the collection, 1895-1902, is between Charles Ryland Burnett, Sr. and his brother Henry Caldwell Burnett (1875-1935), who was employed with the National Bank of Commerce in St. Louis, and sister Malen Burnett (1878-1947), while she was studying and teaching music in St. Charles, Missouri, and in Germany. Subjects include financial matters, investments, and the health and death of their father, Henry Cox Burnett (1839-1902). There are also letters between Charles Ryland Burnett, Sr. and Eugenia Whyte Griffin prior to their marriage, and between her and her father Judge Wingfield Griffin (1846-1930) of Salem, Virginia. Subjects include courtship, social life, health, and family news. Correspondence during the 1940's is mainly between Burnett and his son, Charles Ryland Burnett, Jr., and deals with the latter's investments while he was serving in the Navy during World War II, and his efforts to secure employment in the banking industry following the war.
The post-1950 correspondence is between Charles Ryland Burnett, Jr. and Miriam Louise Weston prior to their marriage in 1954, and their parents and siblings. Following their marriage, Charles and Miriam Burnett lived in Bermuda, England, Fort Lauderdale, Florida, South Africa, and Canada, where Miriam's father, W. Garfield Weston (1898-1978), owned many business enterprises, which Burnett was involved in as a director or president. There is a good deal of correspondence while Charles Burnett, Jr. was president of the Belmont Manor Golf and Country Club in Bermuda, and on the board of directors of Walters Biscuits, Ltd. There are also many letters written between Miriam Burnett and her mother-in-law, parents, and siblings.
Other materials in the collection include information on the Burnett's investments, trust accounts, and other financial matters. There are class notes, school work, and report cards from St. Christopher's School in Richmond, Episcopal High School in Alexandria, Pine Crest School in Fort Lauderdale, Florida, and St. John's College in Johannesburg, South Africa. There are clippings, diaries, garden club materials, greeting cards, insurance papers, invitations, passports, photographs, scrapbooks, and travel brochures and itineraries.
There is also information regarding the Weston Girls' Tour, which was led by Miriam Weston prior to her marriage to Charles Burnett. The tour was funded by Miriam's father, Garfield Weston, and gave 50 young girls from across Canada a chance to travel to England. In 1952, the group witnessed the coronation of Queen Elizabeth II. Also of note in the collection are materials related to the Burnett's interest in research on Parkinson's Disease, as well as the beneficial effects of procaine to prevent or postpone aging. There is correspondence between the Burnett's and Romanian biologist and physician Dr. Anna Aslan (1897-1988), and also the Swedish scientist Dr. Arvid Carlsson (b. 1923).
Contents List
- Address Book. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Addresses. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Affel. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Allied Bakeries Ltd.. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- All's Fair in Love and War by Nina Kirby-Smith Buck, 1945. (Box 1, Folder 4a)
- American Medical Association. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Americans United for Separation of Church and State. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Among Ourselves - Federal Reserve Bank of Chicago, 1922, 1924. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Architectural Drawings - Home Renovations (Three Chopt Road). (Map-case 2, Drawer 13)
- Art. (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
- Aslan, Dr. Anna. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Associated British Foods Ltd.. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Astrology. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bank of Bermuda. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Bank of Nova Scotia. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Bank of Virginia. (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
- Barclays Bank Ltd.. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Belmont Manor Hotel. (Box 2, Folder 4-7)
- Bermuda. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Bermuda - Letters to W. Garfield Weston. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Bessie. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Birth Certificate - Miriam Louise Weston. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Bohannon. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- British Linen Bank. (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
- British Linen Bank - Charlie. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Burnett, Charles Ryland Jr. - War Years and Later. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Burnett, Charles Ryland Jr. and Eugenia Griffin. (Box 3, Folder 6-9)
- Burnett, Charles Ryland Sr., 1895-1902. (Box 3, Folder 10-12)
- Burnett, Charles Ryland III - Birth/Childhood. (Box 4, Folder 1-5)
- Burnett, Charles Ryland III - Friends. (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
- Burnett, Charles Ryland III - School Years. (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
- Burnett, Eugenia Griffin. (Box 5, Folder 5-8)
- Burnett, Eugenia Griffin, 1946-1950. (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Burnett, Wingfield Griffin. (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Calendar, 1970. (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Camp Carolina, 1929. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Camps and Schools - Charlie. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Canada Month. (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Canadian Bank of Commerce, Toronto. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Canadian Bank of Commerce - Checking. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Carlsson, Dr. Arvid. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Cat. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Certificates - Royal School of Music, 1940. (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Chemical Bank & Trust Company. (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Christmas Gifts. (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Christmas Lists, 1954-1973. (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Class Notes, 1940-1941. (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
- Class Notes - Chemistry. (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Class Notes - Navigation. (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Clippings. (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
- Clubs. (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
- Colleges and Universities - Admissions, 1972. (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
- Company Correspondence, 1965-1971. (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Conservative Viewpoint. (Box 7, Folder 10-12)
- Correspondence, 1895-1897. (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1909. (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1911. (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1913. (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1915. (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1917. (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1918. (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1919. (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1921. (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1922. (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1926. (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1927. (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1928. (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1929. (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1930. (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1931. (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1932. (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, 1933. (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 1934. (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, 1937. (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, 1939. (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Correspondence, 1940. (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Correspondence, 1942. (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Correspondence, 1943. (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Correspondence, 1944. (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Correspondence, 1945. (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Correspondence, 1946. (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Correspondence, 1947. (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Correspondence, 1948. (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Correspondence, 1949. (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Correspondence, 1950-1965. (Box 9, Folder 1-17)
- Correspondence, 1966-1974. (Box 10, Folder 1-15)
- Correspondence, 1975-1978. (Box 11, Folder 1-4)
- Correspondence, 1981. (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1983. (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1986. (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1988-1992. (Box 11, Folder 8-12)
- Correspondence, 1996. (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1998. (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, n.d.. (Box 11, Folder 15-16)
- Correspondence Study Program - LSU, 1955. (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Corydon Point Accounts, 1974. (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Dale Carnegie Course, 1951. (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Damage Control - Naval Training School Lectures, 1944. (Box 11, Folder 20-21)
- Daniel, John W., 1881. (Box 11, Folder 21a)
- Diary, 1941-1943. (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Diary, 1945-1947. (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Diary, 1949. (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Donations. (Box 12, Folder 3-5)
- Donations - Literature. (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
- Drugs. (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Educational Trust Fund, 1943. (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Engagement Letters. (Box 12, Folder 10-11)
- Engagement Notes. (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Ephemera. (Box 28)
- Episcopal High School, Alexandria. (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Episcopal High School - Centennial Celebration, 1939. (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Essays. (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Estate of Charles R. Burnett, Sr.. (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Estate of Claudine Griffin Holcomb. (Box 13, Folder 5)
- F.H. Deacon & Company Ltd., 1963-1965. (Box 13, Folder 6)
- First and Merchants National Bank (Richmond, Va.). (Box 13, Folder 7-8)
- First and Merchants Trust Account. (Box 13, Folder 9-12)
- First National Bank (Fort Lauderdale). (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Florida House. (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
- Florida Pool. (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
- Fort Lauderdale Symphony Society, 1967-1968. (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Fortnum & Mason. (Box 14, Folder 6-8)
- Funeral of Eugenia Griffin Burnett, 1981. (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Garden Club. (Box 14, Folder 10-12)
- Genealogical Notes. (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Geriatrics/Gerontology. (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Girls' Tours. (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
- Grandma by Miriam Weston Burnett, 1997. (Box 15)
- Greeting Cards - Anniversary. (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Greeting Cards - Birthday. (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Greeting Cards - Christmas. (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Greeting Cards - Christmas. (Box 16, Folder 1-6)
- Greeting Cards - Easter. (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Greeting Cards - Father's Day. (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Greeting Cards - Get Well. (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Greeting Cards - Mother's Day. (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Greeting Cards - Valentine's Day. (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Guest Lists - Wedding of George Grainger Weston. (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Harbor Defense - U.S. Naval School. (Box 17, Folder 2)
- History. (Box 17, Folder 3)
- House Sale Contract, 1994. (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Howardsgate Holdings Ltd. - Weekly Sales Figures, 1961. (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Insurance. (Box 17, Folder 6-10)
- Investments. (Box 17, Folder 11-14)
- Investments - Card Index. (Box 27)
- Investments - Correspondence. (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Invitations. (Box 18, Folder 2)
- It's Your Money by Walter E. Spahr, 1946. (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Kersten. (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Literature. (Box 18, Folder 5-7)
- Loan - Bank of Nova Scotia. (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Magazines and Subscriptions. (Box 18, Folder 9-11)
- Malen Burnett School of Piano Playing. (Box 18, Folder 12)
- Manion Forum, 1978. (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Maps. (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Marriage Certificate, 1954. (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Marriage License - Joseph Caldwell and Mary Ann Adams, Shelby County, TN, 4 March 1830 (1931 copy). (Box 29)
- Matriculation Englis Examination Questiona. (Box 19, Folder 3)
- The Matrimonial Post and Fashionable Marriage Advertiser, 1944. (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Medical - General. (Box 19, Folder 5-7)
- Medical Records (RESTRICTED - CLOSED UNTIL 2050). (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Membership Cards. (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Membership Certifiate - National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution - Malen Burnett, 7 April 1914. (Box 29)
- Membership Certificate - National Society of the Sons of the American Revolutions - Charles Ryland Burnett, 31 March 1943. (Box 29)
- Mementos (Miriam L. Weston), 1949-1950. (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Memorandum Book. (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Military Newsletters (WWII). (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Lex Miller - Accounts. (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Lex Miller - Correspondence. (Box 19, Folder 14-17)
- Miscellaneous. (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Moore, S. Derrickson. (Box 20, Folder 2)
- National Parkinson Foundation. (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Nature 1999. (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Naval Reserve. (Box 20, Folder 5-6)
- Navy Service Record. (Box 20, Folder 7)
- Notepaper Samples. (Box 20, Folder 8)
- Owner's Manuals. (Box 20, Folder 9)
- Paintings. (Box 20, Folder 10)
- Passports. (Box 20, Folder 11)
- Pay Day by David Milton Proctor, 1936. (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Pay Stubs, 1948. (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Personal - A. (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Personal - H. (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Personal - R. (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Personal - T. (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Photographs. (Box 21, Folder 7-8)
- Pine Crest School. (Box 21, Folder 9-13)
- Pocket Manual of the Negotiable Instruments Law of Virginia, 1937. (Box 21, Folder 14)
- Poker Rules and Suggestions, 1941. (Box 21, Folder 15)
- Political. (Box 21, Folder 16)
- Postcards, n.d.. (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Postcards - Unused. (Box 27)
- Pratt, William K. - Contract, 1970. (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Programs. (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Ration Book (England). (Box 22, Folder 4)
- Receipts (Pre-1970). (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Receipts - General. (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Recogntion Pictorial Manual of Naval Vessels, 1943. (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Recollections of Banks and Bankers Since 1865 by Richard H. Smith, 1939. (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Report Cards - Episcopal High School. (Box 22, Folder 9)
- Report Cards - Richmond Normal School. (Box 22, Folder 10)
- Report Cards - St. Christopher's School. (Box 22, Folder 11)
- Report Cards - Sweet Briar Institute. (Box 22, Folder 12)
- Report Cards - University of Virginia >. (Box 22, Folder 13)
- Resolutions. (Box 22, Folder 14)
- School Compositions. (Box 22, Folder 15)
- Scrapbook - Eugenia Griffin Burnett. (Box 22, Folder 16-17)
- Scrapbook - Grover C. Holcomb. (Box 29)
- Scrapbook - Miriam Louise Weston. (Box 23, Folder 1)
- The Ships and Aircraft of the United States Fleet by James C. Fahey, 1944. (Box 23, Folder 2)
- The Side Boy - United States Naval Reserve, 1941. (Box 23, Folder 3)
- The Signers of the Declaration of Independence. (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Silver and Jewelry. (Box 23, Folder 5)
- Soberman, Isenbaum & Colomby. (Box 23, Folder 6)
- South Africa - St. John's College. (Box 23, Folder 7-8)
- Speech - Eugenia Griffin Burnett, Sweet Briar College, 2 October 1951. (Box 23, Folder 9)
- Stamps. (Box 23, Folder 10)
- Stanford University Directory, 1945-1946. (Box 23, Folder 11)
- Sympathy Letters - Death of Reta Lila Weston. (Box 23, Folder 12-13)
- Taxes, 1946-1948. (Box 24, Folder 1)
- Taxes, 1953. (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Thank You, Congratulations, Sympathy Letters - Examples. (Box 24, Folder 3)
- Three Chopt Road Property (5906). (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Travel. (Box 24, Folder 5-7)
- Travel Diary, 1935. (Box 24, Folder 8)
- Trunk. (Box 24, Folder 9)
- University of Virginia Directory and Graduation Program, 1939-1941. (Box 24, Folder 10)
- Up With People!. (Box 24, Folder 11)
- Via Marsi Montessori School, Milwaukee. (Box 24, Folder 12)
- Vitamin E. (Box 24, Folder 13)
- Walters Biscuits Ltd., 1964-1965. (Box 25, Folder 1-5)
- Walters Biscuits Ltd., 1975-1976. (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Wedding, 1954. (Box 25, Folder 7-8)
- Wedding Invitations and Announcements. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Weston Family Birthdays. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Weston, Grainger. (Box 26, Folder 3-8)
- Weston, W. Garfield - Memorial Service, 25 October 1978. (Box 26, Folder 9)
- Whittington Condominiums. (Box 26, Folder 10)
- Whittington Realty. (Box 26, Folder 11)